Guide to the May Anti-Slavery manuscript collection, 1749-1933.
May Anti-Slavery manuscript collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
May Anti-Slavery manuscript collection, 1749-1933 (bulk 1840-1880)
4601
May, Samuel J.(Samuel Joseph),
10.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, financial records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Consists mainly of correspondence among American abolitionists, including many letters to Samuel Joseph May. Also included correspondence among members of May's family and the family of James Miller McKim; and some correspondence with Daniel Willard Fiske and George William Harris concerning the building of the May Anti-Slavery Collection at Cornell University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Samuel Joseph May (1797-1871) was an American Unitarian minister and civil libertarian, one of the founders of the New England Anti-Slavery Society in 1832 and of the American Anti-Slavery Society in 1833; he also worked for women's rights.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Consists mainly of correspondence among American abolitionists, including many letters to Samuel Joseph May. Also included are May's diaries from 1859-1861 and 1865-1870; correspondence among members of May's family and the family of James Miller McKim; and some correspondence with Daniel Willard Fiske and George William Harris concerning the building of the May Anti-Slavery Collection at Cornell University. Correspondents include Lyman Abbott, John Brown, Henry Grafton Chapman, Maria Weston Chapman, David Lee Child, Lydia Maria Child, Daniel Willard Fiske, William Lloyd Garrison, D.C. Haynes, George William Harris, H.B. Holmes, Oliver Otis Howard, Oliver Johnson, Joseph May, Lucretia F. May, Samuel May Jr., Samuel Joseph May, James Miller McKim, William Forster Mitchell, Lucretia Coffin Mott, Wendell Phillips, Reuben Tomlinson, George Cabot Ward, and Theodore G. Wright.
SUBJECTS
Names:
May, Samuel J. 1797-1871,; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922.; Brown, John, 1800-1859.; Chapman, Henry Grafton.; Chapman, Maria Weston, 1806-1885.; Child, David Lee, 1794-1874.; Child, Lydia Maria, 1802-1880.; Fiske, Willard, 1831-1904.; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879.; Harris, George William, 1849-1917.; Howard, O. O. (Oliver Otis), 1830-1909.; Johnson, Oliver, 1809-1889.; May, Joseph.; May, Lucretia F., -1865.; May, Samuel, Jr., 1810-1899.; Mitchell, William Forster.; M'Kim, J. Miller (James Miller), 1810-1874.; M'Kim, J. Miller (James Miller), 1810-1874; M'Kim, J. Miller (James Miller), 1810-1874.; Mott, Lucretia, 1793-1880.; Phillips, Wendell, 1811-1884.; Tomlinson, Reuben.; Ward, George Cabot.; Wright, Theodore G.; Cornell University. Library.; Cornell University. Library; Freedmen's Aid Organization.
Subjects:
Abolitionists -- United States.; Slavery -- United States.; African Americans -- History -- To 1863.; African Americans -- Civil rights.; Women's rights -- United States -- History.; Domestic relations -- United States.; Abolitionists; African Americans; African Americans -- Civil rights; Domestic relations; Race relations; Slavery; Women's rights
Places:
United States -- Race relations -- History.; United States
Form and Genre Terms:
History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Diaries and other bound manuscripts are cataloged separately and can be found by searching the catalog for collection number 4601.
NOTES
Large book and pamphlet collection concerning slavery and the anti-slavery movement also held in the repository, including slave narratives; abolitionist tracts, sermons, and letters; poetry and hymns, and documents of state governments and organizations concerning slavery.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
This collection came in as a series of donations and has therefore been organized by donation into these series: Maria and Henry Chapman papers, Lydia Maria Child papers, letters and documents from other abolitionists, and Freedmen's Aid Organization.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Maria and Henry Chapman papers (Box 1)
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Group of fragments, Chapman, Maria
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Letter/s to Weston, Caroline
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Letter/s to General Bottex
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    Journal of a voyage to Haiti
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, 1841-1842 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Letter/s to the Editor of "The Manifeste"
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, 1841-1842 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Lists, notes, sketches, receipts
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, February 28, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Letter/s to Chapman, Mary G.
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, May 14, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Letter/s to Chapman, Henry
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, May 14, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Letter/s to Anny
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, May 21, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, June 1, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Poem on letter to Chapman, H. G.
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Letter/s to unknown (fragments)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Letter/s to Channing, William E. (draft, fragments)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Letter/s to Weston, Caroline (fragment)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, January 21, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, January 21, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Letter/s to Lizzy, Henry, Anne and Gertrude
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, January 11, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, January 22, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Letter/s to Weston Warren, Anne
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, January 22, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Letter/s to Weston Warren, Anne; Debora
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, January 24, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, February 1, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, February 1, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Letter/s to Children
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, March 14, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Letter/s to Weston, Caroline; Weston, Anne
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, March 19, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Letter/s to "Dear Friends"
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, May 28, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, May-June, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Letter/s to Weston, Caroline (fragments)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, March 7, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Letter/s to Chapman/Weston families
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, 1842-03-10-1842-03-15 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, March 21, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Letter/s to Elizabeth, Henry and Anne
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, 1843-1863 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Letter/s to McKim, James Miller
  - Chapman, Mary G, July 11, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Cuarcy (?), April 4, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Letter/s to Chapman, Henry Grafton
  - Griffin, William P., May 20, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Letter/s to Chapman, Maria Weston
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Notes on Haitian history
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Haiti Treasure document signed by three officials
  - Chapman, Henry Grafton, March 25, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Letter/s to Dupuy
  - Letter to Cornell about May Anti-Slavery collection, signed by Garrison, May, Smith, and Phillips, October 1, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Series II. Lydia Maria Child papers
  - Manuscripts and Documents
    - "A Riddle. On the letter H", Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Anne Whitney's Model of Charles Sumner; now in New York, and worthy of a place in its Central Park", Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Apple-Seed John", Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - A Song in Gold, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Aspirations of the World, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Autobiography, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Booklet of quotations and poems, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Copies of poems addressed to Lydia Maria Child, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Duplicity - A tale from real life, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Effects of Music, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Essay on Immortality, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Essay on Sorrow, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Flora's Timekeepers. A Fable, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - From Angelina Grimke Speech, 1838-02-21 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - From Angelina Grimke, Liberator, 1838-03-02 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hair clippings, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - How a very small Mouse helped to gnaw open a net that held a great Lion, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Iceland Mice, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Indian Archetypes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Letter from New York…Boston Daily Courier, December 14, 1846, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - List of Employments in 1864, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Mottoes (booklet of quotations), Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Nancy Jane Smith, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "Old Folks at Home", Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Poem in German by Graf von Loeben, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Poems, Undated (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
    - "Praise of Slavery", Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Quotation, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - "Satan in search of a second wife By his first Mother-in-law", Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "Seventy Five", Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Short pieces to be put in to fill up pages if needed, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Simplicity of the Olden Time, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Southern Opinions and Boastings, Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "The Conflict of Life", Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - The Little Beggars, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - "The Monkey's Party. A Fable", Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - "The Old Folks' Room", Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - The Progress of Religious Ideas, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - The Progress of Religious Ideas, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - "To the Spirit of my Beloved Old Mate", 1875 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Translation of a song by Heinrich Heine, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Two poems in memory of Ellis Gray Loring, 1865-05-24 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - "Unmated", Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Watercolor of a Taylor-Bird's Nest, 1834 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Untitled fragment, Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Account of will, 1888-07-26 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Contract with publishers, 1864-11-09 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Copy of the Account of Wendell Phillips, Executor of the Will of Lydia Maria Child, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fifth and final account of estate, 1888-03-27 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Third and final account of estate, 1890-1899 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence - by known correspondent
      Arranged alphabetically.
      - Bullard, Edward Fitch, 1859-12-19 (Box 5, Folder 91)
      - Child, David Lee, 1830-1859 (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
      - Child, David Lee, 1830-1859 (Box 5, Folder 21, 23, 25-26)
      - Child, David Lee, 1830-1859 (Box 5, Folder 31, 35)
      - Child, David Lee, 1830-1859 (Box 5, Folder 47, 50-51)
      - Child, David Lee, 1830-1859 (Box 5, Folder 66, 68-70)
      - Child, David Lee, 1830-1859 (Box 5, Folder 72, 78-79, 81, 90)
      - Curtis, Anna Shaw, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Francis, Convers, 1820-1857 (Box 5, Folder 20, 32, 34, 52, 57-58, 76)
      - Mr. Kimball, 1835-04-10 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - King, Augusta G., 1840-1844 (Box 5, Folder 33, 40, 42, 45)
      - Lesley, Peter, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Loring, Ellis Gray, 1856-02-12 (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - Loring, Mrs. Ellis Gray, 1839-01-12 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - McKim, James Miller, 1841-1843 (Box 5, Folder 37, 41)
      - May, Samuel Joseph, 1866-1867 (Box 6, Folder 28, 31)
      - Osgood, Lucy, 1844-1860 (Box 5, Folder 11-14)
      - Osgood, Lucy, 1844-1860 (Box 5, Folder 44, 46, 48)
      - Osgood, Lucy, 1844-1860 (Box 5, Folder 60, 63-65, 67)
      - Osgood, Lucy, 1844-1860 (Box 5, Folder 73, 75, 77)
      - Osgood, Lucy, 1844-1860 (Box 5, Folder 80, 86-89)
      - Osgood, Lucy, 1844-1860 (Box 5, Folder 1192, 96-97)
      - Osgood, Lucy, 1844-1860 (Box 5, Folder 100, 103, 105)
      - Osgood, Lucy, 1861-1873 (Box 6, Folder 3, 11-12, 19)
      - Osgood, Lucy, 1861-1873 (Box 6, Folder 29, 37, 40)
      - Parsons, Sarah Maria, 1847-1880 (Box 5, Folder 49, 55-56, 62, 93)
      - Publishers of The Atlantic Monthly, Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Sargent, Henrietta, 1836-1860 (Box 5, Folder 27, 29, 43, 82, 99, 101, 1045)
      - Sargent, Henrietta, 1861-1870 (Box 6, Folder 4, 6-7)
      - Scudder, Eliza, 1862-1872 (Box 6, Folder 16, 20-22, 34)
      - Searle, Lucy, 1850-1860 (Box 5, Folder 53, 98, 102)
      - Searle, Lucy, 1861-1862 (Box 6, Folder 5, 13)
      - Shaw, Francis George, 1841-1860 (Box 5, Folder 36, 38-39)
      - Shaw, Francis George, 1861-1880 (Box 6, Folder 59)
      - Shaw, Sarah B., 1850-1860 (Box 5, Folder 16-17, 54, 59, 71, 74, 83-85, 95)
      - Shaw, Sarah B., 1861-1880 (Box 6, Folder 10, 60)
    - Correspondence - Unknown and Unsorted
      Arranged chronologically.
      - Unknown correspondent, 1820-1860 (Box 5, Folder 1-8, 24, 28, 94)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1861 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1863 (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1864 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1865 (Box 6, Folder 24-25)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1866 (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1867 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1868 (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1869 (Box 6, Folder 35-36)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1870 (Box 6, Folder 38-39)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1871 (Box 6, Folder 41-42)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1872 (Box 6, Folder 43-44)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 45-46)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1874 (Box 6, Folder 47-48)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1875 (Box 6, Folder 49-50)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1876 (Box 6, Folder 51-52)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1877 (Box 6, Folder 53-54)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1878 (Box 6, Folder 55-56)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1879 (Box 6, Folder 57-58)
      - Unsorted Correspondence, 1880 (Box 6, Folder 56-60)
- Series III. Freedman's Aid Organization (Box 7)
  - Plan of Commission for the relief or National Freedmen, signed by Ward, G.C., December 2, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Drafts of Constitution of the Western Department of the American Freedmen's Aid Commission, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Two records of the Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands, February, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Copy of Minutes of the Executive Committee of the American Freedmen's Aid Commission, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of "North Western Freedman's Aid", Chicago meeting, August 25, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Two Certificates for delegates to represent The Northwestern Freedmen's Aud Commission at the two conventions held in D.C., February 5, 1864, February 9, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Letter by Abbott, Lyman to Rev. Walden, with list of the General Agents of the Freedmen Commission, February 23, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors of the North Western Freedmen's Aid Commission, with list of names, 1866-1867 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Two lists of State Superintendents of Education, May, 1869 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Monthly Report of a Colored School…", known as the Mattapan School in Eastville, Virginia, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Supplemental Report of E and M. A. Darrow account, May, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Statement of the condition of the 75 schools in South Carolina byt the State Superintendent of Education, May, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Consolidated State Superintendent Monthly School Report to Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands, May, 1867 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - New York Branch Freedmen's Union Commission Teacher's school report, May, 1869 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Four identical blank forms of schedule of schools and rental accounts, Undated undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Three reports of Collecting Agents of the North Western Freedmen's Aid Commission, 1866-1867 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Notification about the transfer to the Association of School Buildings, November 11, 1868 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letters from General Supt. Schools, regarding accounts, reports, forms, etc., April 17, 1869 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Printed Form of a "Treasurer's Receipt", Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fourteen pages of a preliminary financial statement covering schools in charge of the commission, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Printed circular, "How can American Slavery be Abolished?", November 16, 1860 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Printed circular giving an account of the work so far performed, with a program for the future, October 9, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Announcement of the opening of an office of the American Freedmen's Aid Commission in D.C., signed Shipher, Jacob R., October 17, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Printed circular, meeting to be held in D.C., December 13, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Printed circular, "The National Thanksgiving", November 15, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Printed circular, "Thanksgiving", December 7, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - (facsimile) National Freedmen's Aid Union, "Lancashire Dirstress Surplus Fund", July 9, 1867 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - (facsimile) "The Address…to the Earl of Derby", Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands transportation orders for teachers form, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands transportation order for Mrs. S.O Snelling, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Three transportation orders in the name of Mrs. S. O. Snelling, October 8, 1868 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Six transportation orders in the name of Phineas Colver, November 17, 1868 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Circular Letter No. 1, Maj. Gen. O.O. Howard announces appointment, May 15, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Article of Agreement: Freedmen's Orphans Home Indenture of Narcissa McNeil, September 14, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Western Sanitary Commission letter from Rev. J. Forman to Walden, J.M., October 24, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Request for a teacher, November 16, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - T. Harrison enclosing applications for teachers as Arkadephia and letters, 1865-1866 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Relation between the Memphis Colored Orphan Asylum and the Northwest Freedmen Commission" letters by Canfield, S.A.M. to Walden, Rev. J.M., February-July, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Two letters by Abbot, Lyman to Eddy, T.M. and Walden, J.M., May, 1860 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Copy of contract "imposed upon freedmen who could not write…", 1867 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Old MSS numbers 49-60: Letters and fliers regarding the building of the May Anti-Slavery Collection, 1867-1876 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Document from "The undersigned citizens of Philadelphia…" protesting admission of Texas to the Union, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Portraits of American Abolitionists, Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Lawrence, Fannie Virginia Casseopia; Child, Lydia Maria Francis; Douglass, Frederick; Garrison, William Lloyd; Giddings, Joshua Reed; Phillips, Wendell; Seward, William H; Smith, Gerrit
  - Collection indexes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Three signed petitions from Massachusetts to end slave hunting and slave trade, 1860 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Unidentified individuals
  - Certificate of search for slaves on board a vessel, February 15, 1860 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Slave sellers cards, Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Series IV. Correspondence and Documents from Other Abolitionists
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by author. Documents are arranged by author or associated name.
  - Catalogue of collection letters, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - A-F
    - Abbott, Benjamin Vaughan, August 20, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Abbott, Lyman, 1866-1868 (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
      Letter/s to Allan, George H.; Brewer, Rev. Fisk P.; McKim, James Miller; May, Samuel Jr.; Shaw, Francis George; Walden, Rev. John Morgan
    - Adams, E.B., May 9, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Adams, Sarah A., November 22, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Application for teaching position
    - Agnew, Cornelius Rea, January 24, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Letter/s to Collins, Charles
    - Akin, Jonathan, May 2, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Albright, Arthur, 1865-1868 (Box 9, Folder 8-11)
      Letter/s to Resolution; McKim, James Miller; Mitchell, William Forster; Shipherd, Jacob R.; Walden, John Morgan; unknown
    - Allan, George H., 1866-1867 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Letter/s to Abbott, Lyman; McKim, James Miller
    - Allen, William Frederick, January 14, 1868 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Alston, Annie E., February 1869 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      Receipt
    - Alvord, Henry Elijah, August 29, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Letter/s to Dike, Henry A.
    - Alvord, J.W., 1866-1869 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Letter/s to Abbott, Lyman; Holmes, H.B.; McKim, James Miller; Northwestern Branch AFUC
      Sewall, F.D.
    - American Freedmen's Aid Union, February 10, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      Constitutional Articles
    - American Freedmen's Association, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      Estimated Income or Expenditure of the American Freedmen's Association
    - American School Apparatus Co., The, 1868-1869 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      Itemized Receipt for Cardoza, T.W.; Itemized receipt for National Freedmen's Association
    - Anderson, Charlotte E., November 19, 1869 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      Letter/s to Mrs. Lowell
    - Anderson, E.B., November 4, 1869 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Anderson, Matilda C., July 7, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      Letter/s to Israel, Fielder
      Anderson, Charlotte E.
    - Andrew, C.R., June 25, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      Brewer, Fisk P.
    - Andrew, John Albion, May 4, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Andrews, Orville T., 1866-1869 (Box 9, Folder 25a)
      Letter/s to Collins, Ellen; McKim, James Miller
    - Anonymous, November 9, 1795 (Box 9, Folder 25b)
      Letter/s to Sharpe, Samuel
    - Arbuthnot, Robert, December 30, 1736 (Box 9, Folder 26)
      Letter/s to Report of our Proceedings upon the weighty affair of the late Conspiracy of our Slaves
    - Andrey, William, January 13. 1868 (Box 9, Folder 27)
      Letter/s to Mason, R.B.
    - Armistead, Wilson, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 28)
      Letter/s to McKim, James Miller; unknown
    - Armstead, Mary F., Undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
      4 paychecks
    - Armstrong, Edward, January 21, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Armstrong, William H., December 25, 1859 (Box 9, Folder 31)
      Letter/s to Child, Lydia Maria
    - Arnold, J.N., October 17, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Arnott Bros. & Co., January 31, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Arnott, Thomas R., 1866-1867 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Ashcom, Samuel, March, 1783 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      Bond
    - Ashley, James Monroe, 1859-1861 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Atkinson, Thomas, June 27, 1861 (Box 9, Folder 37)
      McKim, James Miller; Mott, James
    - Bachelor, D.T., Undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
      Letter/s to unknown
    - Bachelor, Ella B., Undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
      Letter/s to Bachelor, D.T.
    - Bacon, D. Francis, November 22, 1859 (Box 9, Folder 39)
      Letter/s to Brown, Mary Ann Day (Mrs. John); McKim, James Miller
    - Bacon, Harriet E., 1868-1869 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Bacon, T.L., January 13, 1868 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Bagby, J.P., June 28, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 42)
      Letter/s to President of the Freedmens Educational Society
    - Bailey, William S., June 4, 1860 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Baird, George William, May 6, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 44)
      Letter/s to Corson, Robert Rodgers
    - Baker, George E., 1866-1867 (Box 9, Folder 45)
      Letter/s to May, Samuel J.; Newton, A.E.